Emilio H. Corpus

1876 N. Forest Hill Pl., Danville, CA | emiliocorpus@gmail.com | www.emiliocorpus.com | Cell: 925-708-0062

SUMMARY

Experienced web developer with expertise in Ruby on Rails and React.js who implores a commitment to excellence when designing applications. Can be easily trained and brought up to speed, and prides himself in working well under pressure. Loves the challenge of learning new technologies on the fly and finds great satisfaction in debugging.

PORTFOLIO

FITBITGRAPHS | project | github

FitbitGraphs is constructed with Ruby on Rails and the FitbitAPI with the intent to better visualize data collected by Fitbit trackers. This application currently utilizes Charts.js to plot calories burned and steps taken over a 30-day time span. Other technologies used include JQuery, boostrap, and Heroku.

PERSONAL WEBSITE | project | github

My personal website designed with Ruby on Rails and JQuery, this serves as my way of reaching out towards the online community and showcasing my many projects. It is deployed on *Heroku* and utilizes *boostrap* and a *PostgreSQL* database.

POKÉDEX | project | github

Single-page application created with *Ruby on Rails* and *React.js*, this application was constructed to better understand the fundamentals of *React.js*, specifically how items can be added, deleted, searched and shuffled in the virtual DOM. Other technologies include *Nokogiri* (for parsing Pokémon data), *Heroku* for deployment and *PostrgreSQL* for the database.

BATTLESHIP | project | github

My first single-page application constructed with *Ruby on Rails* and *React.js*. This application was one of the first applications I made with *React.js* and allowed me to truly understand the nature and mechanics of the library. It also allowed me to understand how to implement my own design strategies and is also deployed on *Heroku*.

TWENTY-FOUR | project | github

Twenty-Four was also constructed with Ruby on Rails and React.js and gave me more experience in design strategies. It is a single-page, 2 or more player dice game that utilizes ReactFlipMove library for animations. Other technologies include Heroku for deployment.

AC DC STATS | project | github

AC/DC Stats was also constructed with Ruby on Rails and React.js. As an avid Raider fan I thought it would be fitting to make an application that documents the statistics of players Amari Cooper and Derek Carr throughout the NFL season. It uses Nokogiri for scraping NFL's website and is currently deployed on Heroku.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Dev Bootcamp Coding School, San Francisco, CA, 2015

Dev Bootcamp is an immersive web development course spanning 18+ weeks with a main focus in Object Oriented Javascript, HTML/CSS, and Ruby on Rails. Students are exposed to the fundamentals of web app design, development strategies, best practices, and algorithm application. DBC also teaches students it's unique course of "Engineering Empathy", a concept in which students learn the keys to successfully building relationships with their future co-developers in and outside of the workplace.

Student/Teaching Assistant, 2015

- · Refactoring and code reviews
- Mentor and guide students towards implementing best-practices and design structure
- Constant exposure to new mechanisms and strategies for approaching certain problems

John Muir Medical Emergency Room, Walnut Creek, CA, 2012–2015 Emergency Room Medical Scribe, 2012–2015

- Create and manage physician chart templates
 - · Collaborate with physicians and other healthcare professionals to maintain an efficient workflow
 - Compile, write and edit patient histories, physical exams, medical decision making

University of California-Irvine, 2008-2012

Research Lab Assistant, Dr. Michael R. Rose, 2011

- Maintain lab setting and materials
- · Dividing and organizing test specimens by gender

QUALIFICATIONS

- Ruby/Ruby On Rails
- HTML5/CSS3
- SQL/PostgreSQL
- UNIX Command Line
- Git/Github
- Heroku
- SCRUM & Agile Development

- Object Oriented Javascript
- React.js
- JQuery
- Webpack/NPM
- CRUD & RESTful Web Services
- Peer Programming
- MVC

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

Bachelor of Science, Biology, University of California-Irvine, Irvine, CA 2012

Web Development, Dev Bootcamp, 2015